A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Finance, 2017-2022 (bulk 2018-2021)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Finance, 2017-2022 (bulk 2018-2022)
The Library of Virginia
53509
7.7 cu. ft (22 boxes)
Virginia Secretary of Finance
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Restricted documents have been sealed within the collection. Types of records restricted include, but are not limited to: state income tax returns and workers' compensation reports.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 7 January 2022 by the Virginia Office of the Secretary of Finance, 1111 East Broad Street, Richmond, VA 23219.
Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties, compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governors top management team or "secretariats," as they are called now. The General Assembly in 1972 created six Secretariats positions initially. As government reorganized, that number fluctuated when government agencies expanded or consolidated.
Since the establishment of a secretarial system in 1972, there have been several reorganizations of that system. The financial management function of the state has shifted from under the direction of the Secretary of Finance to the Secretary of Administration; then to Secretary of Administration and Finance and currently back to the Secretary of Finance, through various reorganizations of state government from 1970's to the present. The function of the secretary is to provide sound fiscal management and recommend to the Governor a comprehensive budget for those agencies under his jurisdiction. The secretary's responsibilities are: to monitor programs, services and performance of subordinate state agencies to develop state policies programs for long-range planning and policy formulation; and approve solicitation or acceptance of any donations, gifts or grants; to hold agency heads accountable for their agency's administrative, fiscal and program performance. All secretaries are appointed by the governor and serve at his will.
During the administration of Governor Ralph Northam (2018-2022), the Secretary of Finance was responsible for the direction or jurisdiction over the following agencies and boards: Dept. of Accounts, Dept. of Planning and Budget; Dept. of Taxation, Department of the Treasury, the Virginia Resources Authority, and the Virginia Board of Accountancy.
Governor Ralph Northam appointed former Secretary of Transportation Aubrey Layne Jr. to serve as Secretary of Finance. Upon Layne's resignation in June 2021, Governor Northam appointed Joe Flores as secretary. Flores served until the end of Governor Northam's Administration in 2022.
Scope and Content
Records, 2017-2022, of Secretary of Finance Aubrey Layne Jr. and Secretary of Finance Joe Flores during the administration of Governor Ralph Northam. The collection is housed in 22 boxes and includes budget and financial presentations, decision briefs, revenue reports, correspondence, and Secretary of Finance department subject files. Information on the COVID-19 pandemic; Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security (CARES) Act funds; American Rescue Plan Act (ARPA) funds; and other coronavirus relief funds can be found throughout the collection.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Joint Money Committee Files, 2018-2021
Series II. Decision Briefs, 2017-2022
Series III. Revenue Reports, 2018-2021
Series IV. Correspondence and Subject Files, circa 2018-2022.
Contents List
- Series I. Joint Money Committee Files, 2018-2021., Extent: 0.35 cu. ft (1 box).
  Series I: Joint Money Committee Files, created and maintained by Secretary of Finance Aubrey Layne Jr. and Secretary of Finance Joe Flores, during the administration of Governor Ralph Northam. This series contains presentations to the Joint Money Committee and their cited reports. Topics include state budget, revenue reports, tax impact assessments, and fiscal trends and forecasts. Only the electronic file is available for the December 2021 Joint Money Committee presentation.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Review of General Fund Revenues and the Virginia Economy for Fiscal Year 2018; A presentation to the Senate Finance, House Appropriations and House Finance Committees, 2018 Aug 17. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Governor Northam's Proposed Amendments to the 2018-2020 Budget; Economic Outlook and Revenue Forecast: A briefing for the Senate Finance, House Appropriations and House Finance Committees, 2018 Dec 18. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Review of General Fund Revenues and the Virginia Economy for Fiscal Year 2019; A presentation to the Senate Finance, House Appropriations and House Finance Committees (1 of 2), 2019 Aug 20. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Review of General Fund Revenues and the Virginia Economy for Fiscal Year 2019; A presentation to the Senate Finance, House Appropriations and House Finance Committees (2 of 2), 2019 Aug 20. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Governor Northam's Proposed 2020-2022 Budget; Economic Outlook and Revenue Forecast: A Briefing for the Senate Finance, House Appropriations and House Finance Committees, 2019 Dec 17. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Review of General Fund Revenues and the Virginia Economy for Fiscal Year 2020; Interim Economic Outlook and Revenue Forecast for Fiscal Years 2021 and 2022: A presentation to the House Appropriations, House Finance and Senate Finance and Appropriations Committees, 2020 Aug 18. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Governor Northam's Proposed Amendments 2020-2022 Budget; Economic Outlook and Revenue Forecast: A briefing for the Senate Finance and Appropriations, House Appropriations, and House Finance Committees, 2020 Dec 16. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Review of General Fund Revenues and the Virginia Economy for Fiscal Year 2020; A presentation to the Senate Finance and Appropriations, House Appropriations, and House Finance Committees, 2021 Aug 18. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II. Decision Briefs, 2017-2022., Extent: 5.6 cu. ft (16 boxes).
  Series II: Decision Briefs, created and maintained by Secretary of Finance Aubrey Layne Jr. and Secretary of Finance Joe Flores, during the administration of Governor Ralph Northam. This series contains decision briefs and Secretary of Finance recommendations regarding state finances, including agency requests, coronavirus relief funds, transportation projects, environmental conservation, education programs, and economic development, among others.
  Arranged chronologically by month.
  - Decision Briefs, 2017 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2017 Nov. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2017 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Mar. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 May. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 May. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Jun. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Jun. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Jun. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Jul. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Jul. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Jul. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Aug. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Aug. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Sep. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Oct. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Nov. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Nov. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Nov. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Dec. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Dec. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2018 Dec. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Jan. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Jan. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Feb. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Feb. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Mar. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Mar. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Apr. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Apr. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Apr. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 May. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 May. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Jun. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Jun. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Jun. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Jul. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Jul. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Aug. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Aug. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Sep. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Sep. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Oct. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Oct. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Nov. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2019 Dec. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Jan. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Jan. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Jan. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Feb. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Feb. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Mar. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Mar. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Apr. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Apr. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Apr. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 May. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 May. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Jun. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Jun. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Jun. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Jun. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Jul. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Aug. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Aug. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Sep. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Sep. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Sep. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Oct. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Oct. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Oct. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Oct. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Oct. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Nov. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Nov. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Nov. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Dec. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Dec. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Dec. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2020 Dec. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Jan. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Jan. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Feb. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Feb. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Feb. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Mar. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Mar. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Mar. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Apr. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Apr. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Apr. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 May. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 May. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 May. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Jun. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Jun. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Jun. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Jul. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Aug. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Aug. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Sep. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Sep. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Sep. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Oct. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Oct. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Nov. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Nov. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Dec. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Dec. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Dec. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs, 2021 Jan. (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Series III. Revenue Reports, 2018-2021., Extent: 1.05 cu. ft (3 boxes).
  Series III: Revenue Reports, created and maintained by Secretary of Finance Aubrey Layne Jr. and Secretary of Finance Joe Flores, during the administration of Governor Ralph Northam. This series contains economic and revenue update briefing presentations and reports including information and charts on tax collection, economic indicators, revenue analysis, general fund changes, and economic forecasts.
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2018 Jan. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2018 Feb. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for Richmond Times-Dispatch, 2018 Mar. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2018 Apr. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees (1 of 2), 2018 May. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees (2 of 2), 2018 May. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2018 Sep. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2018 Oct. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2018 Nov. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees (1 of 2), 2019 Jan. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees (2 of 2), 2019 Jan. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2019 Feb. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2019 May. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2019 Jun. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2019 Sep. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2019 Oct. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2020 Jan. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2020 Feb. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2020 May. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2020 Jun. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2020 Sep. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2020 Oct. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees (1 of 2), 2021 Jan. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees (2 of 2), 2021 Jan. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees (1 of 2), 2021 Feb. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees (2 of 2), 2021 Feb. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Hampton Roads Tax Forum, 2021 May 19. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2021 Jun. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2021 Sep. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Economic and Revenue Update: A Briefing for the Money Committees, 2021 Oct. (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Correspondence and Subject Files, circa 2018-2021., Extent: 0.7 cu. ft (2 boxes).
  Series IV: Correspondence and Subject Files, created and maintained by Secretary of Finance Aubrey Layne Jr. and Secretary of Finance Joe Flores, during the administration of Governor Ralph Northam. This series contains department subject files, correspondence, financial statements, and meeting notes. The department subject files contain reports, memorandums, and requests from the departments and boards overseen by the Secretary of Finance. Correspondence includes constituent correspondence on subjects such as tax and state budget concerns, outgoing correspondence relating to state financial actions, and thank you notes.
  Arranged by its original order.
  - Department of Taxation (TAX) (1 of 3), 2018-2022. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Department of Taxation (TAX) (2 of 3), 2018-2022. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Department of Taxation (TAX) (3 of 3), 2018-2022. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Department of Planning and Budget (DPB), 2018-2022. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Department of Accounts (DOA), 2018-2022. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Department of Treasury (TRS), 2020-2021. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Resources Authority (VRA), 2020. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Boards, circa 2018-2022. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Secretary of Finance Financial Statements (1 of 3), 2018-2021. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Secretary of Finance Financial Statements (2 of 3), 2018-2021. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Secretary of Finance Financial Statements (3 of 3), 2018-2021. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Board of Accountancy (VBOA), 2019-2021. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Letters (1 of 4), 2018-2021. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Letters (2 of 4), 2018-2021. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Letters (3 of 4), 2018-2021. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Letters (4 of 4), 2018-2021. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence to Aubrey Layne (1 of 7), circa 2018-2022. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence to Aubrey Layne (2 of 7), circa 2018-2022. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence to Aubrey Layne (3 of 7), circa 2018-2022. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence to Aubrey Layne (4 of 7), circa 2018-2022. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence to Aubrey Layne (5 of 7), circa 2018-2022. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence to Aubrey Layne (6 of 7), circa 2018-2022. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence to Aubrey Layne (7 of 7), circa 2018-2022. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Joe Flores, 2021. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Joe Flores notes (1 of 2), circa 2018. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Joe Flores notes (2 of 2), circa 2018. (Box 22, Folder 12)